Guide to the George Breitman Papers TAM.169
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Series III: Political Organizations and Activities
  - Subseries III:A: Socialist Workers Party
    - Subgroup 1 -- General
      - Club Executive - minutes, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Electoral campaign, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Morrow, Felix: Against the Political Committee's "theses" on the American revolution and "tasks of the SWP in the present political situation", 1946 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Club Executive minutes, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Documents, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Breitman: Electoral analysis, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Breitman: Electoral campaigns, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Breitman: Wallace campaign writings, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Club Executive minutes, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - Frank, E.R. (i.e., Bert Cochran): "...Russian theses", 1948 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Negro Question, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Negro work, report on (Breitman), 1948 (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - San Diego, San Francisco branches, ca.1948 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - Frank, E.R. "...on the evolution of buffer countries", 1949 (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - "Account of an interview with Louis Adamic", 8 pp., April 23rd [confidential - for NC members & alternates only], 1950 (Box 15, Folder 18)
      - Club Executive - minutes, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 19)
      - Electoral campaigns, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - Political "Statements," "Comments," etc. by SWP activists, leaders, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 21)
      - Club Executive minutes, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 22)
      - Electoral campaigns, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 23)
      - Friday Night Socialist forum - Newark, NJ, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 24)
      - Marxist Labor School: "The first American revolution" - lectures outlines, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 25)
      - Political statements, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 26)
      - Documents (includes December report on the 12th NC plenum, 9 pp.), 1952 (Box 15, Folder 27)
      - Breitman - talk re death of Harry T. Moore (African-American), 1952 (Box 15, Folder 28)
      - Club Executive minutes, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 29)
      - Electoral campaigns/analysis, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 30)
      - Friday Night Socialist Forum - Newark, NJ, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 31)
      - San Francisco branch report, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 32)
      - Breitman - notes for talk re: after Stalin's death, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 33)
      - "On Comrade Stein's Article;" "Remarks on 'The Rise and Fall of Stalinism'", 1953 (Box 15, Folder 34)
      - "Clarke's views on Stalinism" [for the Majority Caucus] by W.F. Warde; August 17th, Aug 1953 (Box 15, Folder 35)
      - Club Executive minutes, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 36)
      - Friday Night Socialist Forum - Newark, NJ, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 37)
      - "Introduction to two speeches..." (On the Negro Question), 1953 (Box 15, Folder 28)
      - Kirk, Dick "The Negro Question", 1953 (Box 15, Folder 39)
      - Los Angeles local report (annual), Feb 1953 (Box 15, Folder 40)
      - Negro Question - anonymous statements, theses, ca.1953 (Box 15, Folder 41)
      - Official documents, political statements by members, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 42)
      - Breitman - "American Negro History" - SWP lecture typescript [36 pp], 1954 (Box 16, Folder 0.5)
      - Breitman - Detroit branch - notes, ca.1954 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Cannon (& others) memos to Farrell Dobbs, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Club Executive minutes, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Convention, 16th, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - A dissenting view on The Militant's treatment of the Supreme Court decision by Lois (Los Angeles), 1954 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Electoral campaigns, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - The Lecoeur incident and the perspectives of the C.P.F., 1954 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - McCarthyism (by Breitman?), ca.1954 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - McCarthyism, resolution on: by Dennis Vera, Sam Ryan (Los Angeles), 1954 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - Michigan - ballot fight, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - Negro-Question - correspondence, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - The Negro struggle & the Proletarian revolution by R.S. Fraser, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - The Negro struggle, nationalism, and self-determination (19 pp.) Breitman, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - Newark, NJ activities, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - Newark, NJ branch history/reminiscences, ca.1954 (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - Pabloism correspondence, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - Socialist Union, statement submitted to (re: SWP minority), 1954 (Box 16, Folder 17)
      - Unemployment, Political Committee memorandum, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 18)
      - Automation, preliminary notes on, - by John G. Wright, ca.1955 (Box 16, Folder 19)
      - Breitman: Eastern Europe (notes), ca.1955 (Box 16, Folder 20)
      - Breitman: Emmett Till - lynching, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 21)
      - Breitman: "Lessons of Negro history week" Militant Forum brochure, Cleveland, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 22)
      - Breitman: Reuther, Walter & Henry Ford, ca.1955 (Box 16, Folder 23)
      - Breitman: Soviet Union, Stalinism - notes, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 24)
      - Breitman: Trotsky memorial lecture, ca.1955 (Box 16, Folder 25)
      - Cannon-Dobbs correspondence, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 26)
      - China (SWP Documents), 1955 (Box 16, Folder 27)
      - Club Executive - minutes, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 28)
      - Hanson, Joseph: Some problems in assessing the Chinese revolution (40 pp.), 1955 (Box 16, Folder 29)
      - Michigan - ballot fight, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 30)
      - Minneapolis branch, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 31)
      - National Committee, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 32)
      - Negro Question correspondence, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 33)
      - "Negro Question, for the materialist conception of" (by R.S. Fraser), 1955 (Box 16, Folder 34)
      - Pabloism correspondence, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 35)
      - Pabloism revisited - from Pablo to Cochran, Clarke and Mestre (by Peng) 23 pp., 1955 (Box 16, Folder 36)
      - Quotas & payments in last fund campaign, Jan 1955-Mar 1955 (Box 16, Folder 37)
      - "The Soviet Union", ca.1955 (Box 16, Folder 38)
      - Breitman correspondence w. Earnest Germain (i.e. Mandel) others re Pabloism, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Breitman Detroit branch organizer (talk on his work), ca.1956 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Breitman: Detroit lectures re Negro struggle, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Cannon: Proposals for a propaganda campaign, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Club Executive minutes, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Detroit branch, ca.1956 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Electoral Campaign, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - "Federal troops to Mississippi" resolution discussion, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - "Israeli-Egyptian conflict" 8 pp. (by Dan Roberts), 1956 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Los Angeles branch, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - National Committee, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Report on "Regroupment" conference called by A.J. Muste (NYC), 7 pp. by Tom Kerry, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - American forum, transcript of a report on, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Breitman: Lenin, Leninism - notes, lecture, ca.1957 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Breitman: Lincoln & Washington birthday's celebration lecture, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Breitman: 20th Congress (CPSU), aftermath - notes, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Club Executive minutes, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Communist Party (USA), memorandum on (secretarial draft), 1957 (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - Convention, 17th New York City, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - Internal documents, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - Pabloism correspondence, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 21)
      - Breitman: Humor, other topics - notes, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - Breitman: UDF symposium notes, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - Club Executive minutes, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 24)
      - Independent Socialist Vote (NYS) - report as of November 25th, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - Little Rock (Arkansas) crisis, resolution on by R. Kirk, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 26)
      - Memos, "resolutions" etc. by SWP activists, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 27)
      - National Committee, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 28)
      - Breitman: African-Americans - notes, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 29)
      - Breitman: Khrushchev & Reuther - notes, ca.1959 (Box 17, Folder 30)
      - Club Executive minutes (including documents re. Pabloism), 1959 (Box 17, Folder 31)
      - Detroit branch, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 32)
      - Internal documents & correspondence, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 33)
      - Michigan electoral campaign, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 34)
      - Political Committee minutes, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 35)
      - Resident National Committee minutes, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 36)
      - Weiss, Murry: Memorandum on policy towards the Rubenstein group, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 37)
      - Young Socialist Alliance, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 38)
      - Breitman: notes, talks, writings, 1960s (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Detroit branch, ca.1960 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Electoral campaign, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Detroit (Freedom Now Party, other), 1960s (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Memos, correspondence, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - National Executive Committee minutes, Oct 1960 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Political Committee minutes, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Resident National Committee minutes, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Warde- lecture on contradiction, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Breitman: A. Philip Randolph, Walter Reuther - notes, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Breitman: Freedom Riders (lecture), 1961 (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Breitman: Socialism, nationalism & the Negro struggle (discussion series, NY), 1961 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Convention, 19th New Jersey, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence: Political Committee, Farrell Dobbs, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Detroit branch, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - Electoral campaigns, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - National Committee Plenum minutes, Jan 1961 (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - Political Committee minutes, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - National Committee, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 19)
      - National office - correspondence/documents, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 20)
      - Political Committee, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 21)
      - Breitman: The class struggle road to Negro equality, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 22)
      - Breitman: "The major radical parties - why can't they get together?", 1963 (Box 18, Folder 23)
      - Detroit branch, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 24)
      - Convention 20th (NYC) - Freedom Now resolution, etc., 1963 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Dobbs, Farrell: correspondence, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - "For the right of organized tendencies to exist within the Party" (NYC) Minority statement, Feb. 22, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Freedom Now Party, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - National Committee, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Political Committee, ca.1963 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - SWP/YSA documents, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Vernon, Robert "Why White radicals are incapable of understanding Black nationalism", 1963 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Detroit branch, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Electoral campaigns, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Freedom Now Party, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - National Executive Committee, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Political Committee, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Wohlforth tendency (Pabloites), 1964 (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - YSA, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - Convention, 21st (NYC), 1965 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Electoral campaigns, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - National Committee, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Political Committee, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Breitman - lectures, notes, ca.1965 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Breitman - MacBird lecture, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Breitman "Two proposals", 1966 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Cannon "to the secretariat" (re party discipline), 1966 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - National Committee Plenum minutes, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Should socialists support peace candidates? (YSA discussion paper submitted to the 2nd National Convention of the W.E.B. DuBois Clubs, Jun 1966 (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Internal documents, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Black Fraction, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Black Fraction - District of Columbia, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - Black Fraction - Los Angeles, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - The case for an independent Black political party, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - Political Committee, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 16)
      - SWP/YSA, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 17)
      - Black Fraction, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 19)
      - Electoral campaign, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 20)
      - National Committee, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - Political Committee, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 22)
      - Chicago branch, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 23)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 24)
      - Political Committee, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 25)
      - Internal documents, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - National Committee, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Political Committee, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Internal documents, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Breitman: "Contribution to discussion of leadership question", 1972 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Internal documents, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Internal documents, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Internal documents, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Internal documents, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Electoral campaign, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Hansen, Bea "Some organizational principles of the Party", ca.1976 (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - Internal documents, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - Internal documents, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - Internal documents, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - Internal documents, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - Constitution, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 16)
      - Convention, Oberlin, OH, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 17)
      - Convention, Oberlin, OH - Political Committee Resolution, etc., 1981 (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Internal documents, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence (no month/date given), 1982 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, Jan 1982 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, Feb 1982 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, Mar 1982 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, Apr 1982 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, May 1982 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, Jun 1982 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, Jul 1982 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, Aug 1982 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence, Sep 1982 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, Oct 1982 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, Nov 1982 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, Dec 1982 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Electoral campaigns, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Membership & finances, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Socialist Educational and Activists Conference, Oberlin, OH, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - "BLOC SC"1, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - California SWP, draft counter-resolution, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence & internal documents (no month/date), 1983 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, Jan 1983-Aug 1983 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence, Sep 1983-Dec 1983 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Camejo, Peter - Cuba, Central America, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - "Don't tighten the SWP or you'll strangle it to death" - t.s. for a pamphlet [4 Cannon pieces + GB intro; 27 pp], ca.1983 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Expelled members conference, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Fourth Internationalist Caucus, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Kutcher, James, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - New York, New Jersey - membership/mailing list, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Political Bureau, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Socialist Educational Conference, Oberlin, OH, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - United Secretariat, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Weiss, Myra Tanner: "Dear Comrades", 1983 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence, internal documents, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - List of splitters/end of the split operation, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - Internal documents, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - SWP chronology of events, 1981-1984, undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Subgroup 2 -- Educational Activities
      - Basic training course, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Capital (Karl Marx), undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - "Communist League of America, the crisis in", ca.1982 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - "Fourth International, rocky road to the", 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Fundamentals of Marxism, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - "International Left Opposition, The crisis in, 1930-33", ca.1982 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - National tape service (SWP) catalog, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - "Party history", 1982 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - "International program, [the] liberating influence of", 1974-1975 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - "SWP on the March" - film script, 1948 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - "You the movement in the 1930s - chapters in early Party history", ca.1982 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Subgroup 3 -- Publications Committee
      - Merit Publishers correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Merit Publishers minutes, 1968-1970 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Pathfinder Press correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Pathfinder Press correspondence, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Pathfinder Press correspondence, Jan 1973-'Jun 1973 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Pathfinder Press correspondence, Jul 1973-'Dec 1973 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Pathfinder Press documents, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Pathfinder Press correspondence, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Pathfinder Press correspondence, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Pathfinder Press correspondence, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Pathfinder Press correspondence, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Pathfinder Press correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Pathfinder Press correspondence, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Pathfinder Press ephemera, undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - SWP Publications Committee minutes, 1965-1972 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Subgroup 4 -- FBI Files, general
      - Breitman, Dorothea (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Breitman FOIA Correspondence, 1982-1986 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Detroit Friday Night Forum, 1954-1958 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Detroit Friday Night Forum, 1959-1960 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - Detroit Friday Night Forum, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Detroit Friday Night Forum, 1962-1963 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - Detroit Friday Night Forum, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Detroit Friday Night Forum, 1965-1967 (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - SWP vs. Attorney general - Breitman, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - SWP vs. Attorney general - Mandigo, Charles, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - SWP vs. Immigration & Naturalization Service (INS), 1964-1981 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Subgroup 5 -- FBI Files, James Kutcher
      - Kutcher-Breitman correspondence, 1958-1981 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration: Mar-Aug 1948, Mar 1948-Aug 1948 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration: Sep-48, Sep 1948 (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration: Oct-Nov 1948, Oct 1948-Nov 1948 (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration: Dec-48, Dec 1948 (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration: Jan-Feb 1949, Jan 1949-Feb 1949 (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration: Mar-49, Mar 1949 (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration: Apr-Nov 1949, Apr 1949-Nov 1949 (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration, 1950 (Box 31, Folder 9)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration, 1951 (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration: Jan-Feb 1953, Jan 1953-Feb 1953 (Box 31, Folder 12)
      - Kutcher-Veterans administration: Mar-May 1953, Mar 1953-May 1953 (Box 31, Folder 13)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration: Jun-53, Jun 1953 (Box 31, Folder 14)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration: Jul-Nov 1953, Jul 1953-Nov 1953 (Box 31, Folder 15)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration, Appeals Board hearing, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 16)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration, 1954 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration: Jan-Jun 1956, Jan 1956-Jun 1956 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration: Jul-Dec 1956, Jul 1956-Dec 1956 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration, 1957 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration "Charge", undated (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration correspondence, undated (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - Kutcher-Veterans Administration documents - misc., undated (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - Kutcher, James - FBI Files (1 of 2): [1948-1953], ca.1948-1953 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Kutcher, James - FBI Files (2 of 2): [1948-1953], ca.1948-1953 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Kutcher, James - FBI Files: [1948-1968], ca.1948-1968 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Kutcher, James - FBI Files: [1949-1956], ca.1949-1956 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Kutcher, James - FBI Files: [1949-1956], ca.1949-1956 (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - Kutcher, James - FBI Files: [1949-1956], ca.1949-1956 (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - Kutcher, James - FBI Files: [1953-1965], ca.1953-1965 (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - Kutcher, James - FBI Files (1 of 4): [1952-1956], ca.1952-1956 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Kutcher, James - FBI Files (2 of 4): [1952-1956], ca.1952-1956 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - Kutcher, James - FBI Files (3 of 4): [1952-1956], ca.1952-1956 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - Kutcher, James - FBI Files (4 of 4): [1952-1956], ca.1952-1956 (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - Kutcher, James - FBI Files (1 of 2): [1956], ca.1956 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Kutcher, James - FBI Files (1 of 2): [1956], ca.1956 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - Kutcher, James - FBI Files: [1956-1965], ca.1956-1965 (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - Kutcher, James - FBI Files (1 of 2): [1956-1973, 1981], ca.1956-1981 (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - Kutcher, James - FBI Files (1 of 2): [1956-1973, 1981], ca.1956-1981 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Subseries III:B: Other Organizations (alphabetical listing)
    - American Workers Party, 1934-1935 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Communist League of America - Breitman notes, undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Communist League of America, 1929 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Communist League of America, 1930 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Communist League of America (minutes), 1931 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Communist League of America (minutes), 1932 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Communist League of America - other internal documents, 1932 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - CLA - situation in the American opposition, prospect & retrospect 32 pp. By Shachtman, Glotzer, Ahern: 4-Jun-32, Jan 1932 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Communist League of America (minutes), 1933 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Communist League of America (minutes), 1934 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Fourth International - Breitman notes, undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Fourth International "The Native Question" (Breitman, re South Africa), undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Fourth International, 1930 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Fourth International, 1931 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Fourth International, 1932 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Fourth International, 1933 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Fourth International, 1934 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Fourth International, 1935 (Box 36, Folder 8)